Michał Wadowski

Senior Java Developer

Michał is software development passionate with over 14 years of experience in various technologies and languages. He has been working in Java oriented projects for 5 years using Spring Boot technologies. He values clean code, TDD and other good programming practices.

Professional experience

Mindbox S.A.

HSBC Service Delivery (Polska) Sp. z o.o.

08.2022 - 12.2024

Senior Java Developer

Developing "Strategic Financial Planning" - internal business application in Java 8 - 21 using

Spring Boot in microservices architecture.

PostgreSQL/Oracle, ReactJS and Jenkins was

used in project.

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2022 - 07.2022

Developing microservices for streaming platform using Kafka, MongoDB and Java

Reactor

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

02.2021 - 07.2022

Developing Eclipse Leshan library

https://www.eclipse.org/leshan for IoT

communication protocol (Lightweight M2M).

Orange Polska S.A.

Java Developer

08.2020 - 07.2022

Developing research application ThingIn The

City using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL

technologies.

Orange Polska S.A.

Android Developer

03.2020 - 01.2021

Developing mobile application for technicians

using Live Objects platform

https://liveobjects.orange-business.com with Android Studio in Java and Kotlin languages.
As a development model was used SCRUM

framework.

Awans Sp. z o. o.

Full-stack Developer

06.2014 - 02.2020

Developing https://awanser.pl business

platform using technologies:

Backend: PHP and CakePHP framework,

PostgreSQL database system Frontend: ReactJS with Redux and Ecmascript 6, CSS, LESS and SCSS

Contact

Address

Warsaw, Poland

Phone

+48 796 334 459

E-mail

wadosm@gmail.com

Github

https://github.com/Michal-Wadowski

Experience and knowledge

Programming languages / technologies

Java: Spring Boot, JUnit, Hibernate, Lombok, Java Reactor, Kafka

Databases

PostgreSQL/pgSQL, Oracle, MongoDB

Other tools

Maven, GIT, Docker compose, Jenkins

Good practices

TDD, DDD, Clean architecture, software

design patterns

IDE

IntelliJ IDEA

Operating systems

Linux, Windows

Software Development Model

SCRUM

Languages and technologies in past

Android in Kotlin

Javasript: ECMAScript 6, JSX, ReactJS,

Redux, ¡Query

Python: NUMPY, Keras

C, C++

Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 01.2013 - 05.2014	Java Developer Developing integration layer with ePUAP system in Java and PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
Zeto Olsztyn Sp. z o. o. 10.2011 - 12.2012	Software Developer Developing of business application in Delphi and, PostgreSQL + PL/pgSQL
iDelfi Polska Sp. z o. o. 11.2009 - 12.2010	Full-stack Developer Developing internet application for HACCP management in technologies: Ruby on Rails, Javascript, jQuery, MySQL
Training	
March 2022	Professional Scrum Developer <u>I (PSD I)</u>
Education	

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

University of Warmia and Mazury in Olsztyn

Field of study: Computer science

Field of study: Computer systems

Undergraduate course

M. Sc.

2009 - 2011

2005 - 2008

Courses

Creating µServices using Spring Cloud and Docker

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Spring Framework II

https://www.altkomakademia.pl

Pragmatic refactoring using DDD techniques

https://bottega.com.pl

Clean Code in Java

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Test-Driven Development in practice

https://pragmatists.thinkific.com

Useful characteristics

Writing good quality code

Experienced in working with legacy systems

IT technologies quick learner

Teamwork skills

Independence and responsibility

Languages

Polish

Native

English

B2

Passions & hobbies

Programming microcontrollers and developing electronic circuits

Building and training artificial neural networks

Developing applications and devices for own needs

Astronomy, quantum physics and science in general